<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blog by Cat Tate]]></title><description><![CDATA[Blog by Cat Tate]]></description><link>https://caterpi.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 06:12:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Call To Courage]]></title><description><![CDATA[Brené Brown: Call to Courage is a Netflix Original based on her eponymous book. In this TED talk-like documentary, she teaches how courage and vulnerability are more intertwined than we would think.]]></description><link>https://caterpi.github.io/posts/call-to-courage</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://caterpi.github.io/posts/call-to-courage</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;!-- - [Courage is…](#courage-is)
- [Measure of Courage: Vulnerability](#measure-of-courage)
- [Loss](#loss)
- [Starting this blog](#starting-this-blog) --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;trailer&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#trailer&quot; aria-label=&quot;trailer permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Trailer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 42.857142857142854%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;div class=&quot;embedVideo-container&quot;&gt; &lt;iframe title src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gr-WvA7uFDQ?rel=0&quot; class=&quot;embedVideo-iframe&quot; style=&quot;border:0; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;courage-is&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#courage-is&quot; aria-label=&quot;courage is permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Courage Is…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before watching Call to Courage, I thought of courage as big acts of bravery. I’m imagining someone who chooses an untraditional path in life following her dreams. Brown’s talk on courage lies far away from this imagery. Instead, she looks at courage with a more casual lense. It doesn’t always have to be a life-changing decision; we can all be courageous in different parts of our lives such as relationships or work. For example, saying “I love you” first in a relationship is also courage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She defines courage as choosing to show up knowing you will fail. There is no courage without this fear, or more broadly, vulnerability. She uses findings from decades of research as well as personal anecdotes to illustrate the importance of vulnerability in order to be courageous, compassionate, and creative. This is one of my favorite talks I’ve ever listened to. She is funny, inspirational, and educational while keeping it so real. Anyone can relate to her stories at some level. I think I “aww”-ed, cried, and laughed all during this 1-hour talk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;measure-of-courage-vulnerability&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#measure-of-courage-vulnerability&quot; aria-label=&quot;measure of courage vulnerability permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Measure of Courage: Vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown’s 20 years of research finds vulnerability to be the best measure of courage. That is, “you can measure how brave you are by how vulnerable you are willing to be”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the icky emotions like shame, scarcity, fear, anxiety, uncertainty, grief are what make us feel exposed and uncomfortable. We don’t want others to see these emotions in us, but we must let them, because they give birth to love, belonging, and joy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown says, joy is the most vulnerable human emotion. We’re afraid to lean into joy, because we’re afraid that it could be taken away at any moment. I can’t tell you the number of times I’ve imagined something terrible happening to my sisters when we are having a good time and thinking that this could be the last memorable thing we do together. The fear is tangible, especially because we experience glimpses of this or hear stories of loss from others around us. I definitely think about these tragic “what if” situations more often ever since my sister has been really sick. In Brown’s words, I’m dress-rehearsing tragedy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her research shows that people who can truly lean into joy have one thing in common: gratitude. We know listing three things you’re grateful for everyday is proven to improve happiness. So why was I so surprised? First, I think it’s because I feel generally happy, but there’s only a handful of moments I’ve felt pure joy. Even when I did experience joy, the same memories no longer bring me joy later on for lots of other reasons. Over time, I’ve learned to demote the current value of joy in anticipation of how I would feel about it in the future with thoughts like “I don’t want to overvalue these moments with him or her too much, because what if they’re no longer part of my life?” This talk made me realize how I’ve been holding myself back and how much I actually want more joy in all of my relationships. I actively make microadjustments to my thoughts and behaviors to be happier, but I wasn’t doing the same to be more joyful. The goal isn’t to eliminate the fear of loneliness or loss, but to accept them in order to harvest the goods of all relationships. Now, even with the best friendships I have, I acknowledge they may disappear. At first, it was scary to embrace these thoughts, but it made me appreciate the lasting friendships even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./../media/gooey_cookies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gooey_cookies&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brown calls shame, scarcity, fear, anxciety, uncertainty, grief, the gooey center of vulnerability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;loss&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#loss&quot; aria-label=&quot;loss permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Loss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From interviewing subjects who’ve experienced true trauma (mass shooting, child death, genocide, etc.) Brown shares three of her biggest insights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-expressing-gratitude-shows-we-understand-the-magnitude-of-others-loss&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-expressing-gratitude-shows-we-understand-the-magnitude-of-others-loss&quot; aria-label=&quot;1 expressing gratitude shows we understand the magnitude of others loss permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1. Expressing gratitude shows we understand the magnitude of others’ loss.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We feel so guilty talking about what we have in front of others who don’t have it.  For example, I’ve always felt it was insensitive talking about my mom in front of a friend who’s lost hers. This is true even with the closest people in my life. For the longest time, I shied away from confronting my mom about her trauma.
It’s the inner fear of causing pain in someone or coming across insensitive. But Brown points out that when I avoid the subject of loss, I’m taking that opportunity away from the other person as well. However, the bigger realization I had was I needed to have more faith that people are stronger than I give them credit for. Just because it’s a hard subject doesn’t mean they’ll only feel pain or they’re going to break down. I was being weak-minded. I did get to ask my mom about her past recently and she was able to share lots of positive emotions from a subject of pain. In hindsight, I had lacked the emotional strength and faith in my mom. Also, in this particular case, giving space for pain did give space for positive emotions as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-we-miss-the-simple-ordinary-moments-while-chasing-extraordinary-moments&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-we-miss-the-simple-ordinary-moments-while-chasing-extraordinary-moments&quot; aria-label=&quot;2 we miss the simple ordinary moments while chasing extraordinary moments permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2. We miss the simple, ordinary moments while chasing extraordinary moments.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-just-do-the-joyful-thing&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-just-do-the-joyful-thing&quot; aria-label=&quot;3 just do the joyful thing permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3. Just do the joyful thing.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She quotes Stuart Brown who defines play as “time spent without purpose”. I felt personally attacked, because I have the tendency to feel guilty about the time that wasn’t productive. If it’s not work, I want it to go towards self-improvement. Maybe it’s because we millenials have the tendency to be hyper-active and hyper-productive. We’re surrounded by people who are overachievers in all aspects of life, including in the “fun” department. I value adventure and experience, but I’ve become too impatient.  It’s as if I need to do something new and extraordinary every other weekend. Even during quarantine, I see people who are hiking the Half Dome, visiting friends and going places (some are definitely questionable choices), making me feel like I’m not making the most of my time. I tell my friends I’m a boring person now, but the truth is, I’m okay not baking instagram-worthy bread, being alone with my books, and the most exciting things being underwhelmingly ordinary things like seeing a puppy on the street. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-this-blog&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#starting-this-blog&quot; aria-label=&quot;starting this blog permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Starting this Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was intentional to write a piece on vulnerability as my first post. I am neither confident in my writing nor articulate on many topics I’d like to write about. However, in the spirit of being brave, I choose to pursue this small ambition of mine. I end with a quote that Brené starts with in her talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Theodore Roosevelt &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;footer&gt;
			&lt;cite&gt;— Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/cite&gt;
		&lt;/footer&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>